

CONTACT

- **** 07805115685
- afennell@hotmail.co.uk
- Rainhill, Merseyside
- https://github.com/fennand
- in https://tinyurl.com/9wbnpe5t
- www https://andyfenportfolio.vercel.app/

EDUCATION

2002 - 2006 LIVERPOOL JOHN MOORES **UNIVERSITY**

• Business and IT (2:1 BA degree)

2000 - 2002 **RAINHILL SIXTH FORM, A-LEVELS**

• Business Studies (B), English Language (B), History (C), and IT (A)

1995 - 2000 RAINHILL HIGH SCHOOL, GCSES (9 A-C GRADES)

RELEVANT SKILLS















Azure



III Eleventy

Express

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Cross functional team collaboration
- Design/Wireframing
- · Agile methodolgies

ANDREW FENNELL

JUNIOR FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

PERSONAL STATEMENT

After a career change from the criminal justice system to be a Full Stack Developer, I now have over 2 years experience within this industry, including 18 months commercial experience working for an IT outsourcing company. I have now obtained skills working with various team members to develop, plan and implement ideas across a range of web, app and software platforms. I have a passion for solving technical problems and continuously improving the user experience for end users.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer

DEC 2023 - PRESENT

· Currently taking on freelance work, having created static websites for two companies (incorporating HTML, CSS, Javascript, and Tailwind)

Tech Educators

Full Stack MERN Bootcamp

SEPT 2023 - DEC 2023

- · Used HTML, CSS, Javascript, and various libraries to create fully-functional web apps
- · Deployed web apps in the "MERN" stack with MongoDB, Express, React and Node.js
- · Successfully completed two group projects, in the first we had to create a game which utilised local storage for user inputs
- In the final group project, we made an app users can use to find discounts. For this we had to have pages which processed user input, the app feature a server, make use of a third part API, feature user authentication, and used the four HTTP CRUD methods: GET, PUT, POST, and DELETE.

Reach Aware Ltd / The Coder's Guild

Apprentice Software Developer

Jan 2022 - Aug 2023

- · Developed creative skills with a focus on designing the user experience to showcase to clients how websites and user interfaces would look for each project.
- Developed skills to define the user requirements, write tasks, develop the solution and also performed QA testing to debug any issues.
- Built up skills and knowledge in Eleventy, Liquid, Javascript, C++, C#, .Net, AWS infrastructure services and SQL.
- · Used agile development methodologies with the use of Azure DevOps for our planning, git management, APIs, and deployment.
- · Gained valuable commercial experience working with clients across a variety of different industries and iterated on ideas to improve existing features.

Merseyside Probation

Probation Service Officer

Sept 2008 - Jan 2022

- · Developed good organisational skills, having to manage and prioritise a high caseload under a lot of pressure.
- · Fostered good relationships with my inter-agency colleagues, and was the Single Point of Contact in terms of liaison with our partner agencies, utilising communication and team working skills.
- · Monitored and worked with a large caseload of service users in the community, writing regular reports for courts and the prison service.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

As part of my 12 week MERN coding bootcamp, we were tasked with creating apps for our final group projects. I had an idea of creating an app which will show users where they can get discounted meals and/or drinks in the location and time desired of the user. For example, say the user wants to see where they could get cheap food on a Friday night in Liverpool, they would just input that into our app and be provided with the results.

Criteria: Our React Express app had to be mobile-first, have at least three pages with clear navigation, and one of those pages be an About Us page. It also had to have at least two pages which accepted and processed user input, feature a server, make use of a third party API, feature user authentication, and that the app makes at least one use of the four HTTP CRUD methods: GET, PUT, POST, and DELETE.

We could not find an API which provided the information on the bars and restaurants that we wanted, so we seeded this information ourselves to a MongoDB database as our server element. We had user input in the form of filtered lists and buttons, and we used a third party location API to show the venues on a map. We also decided that a venue should be able to add or edit the details of their offers. We made it so venues would need to go through user authentication to access this feature (using Auth0), and then they would be able to use a form to add, edit, or delete information on their offers

In this project, I focused on the issue around our favourites page. I used local storage to make it so users could favourite a deal they liked, and then go to a favourites page where they would all be stored. I also made sure there was a 'remove favourite' option on this page, and I had to disable the 'favourite' button after it had been clicked to prevent issues using local storage. Using my knowledge of Figma I created all the wireframes for this project. I was responsible for the styling of the header, footer, and About Us page. I also fixed issues with our filters on the homepage, so results were only rendered once the search button had been pressed.

Repo: https://github.com/sushaz9/Dealio













